Jennifer Brana

PHD STUDENT, CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

☑ jbrana@cs.cmu.edu | 🎢 jenniferbrana.github.io | 🖸 JenniferBrana | 🛅 jenniferbrana

Research Interests

I am interested in the intersection of hardware and software systems, particularly in the areas of parallel computing and heterogeneous systems. My aim is to increase the scalability and sustainability of future computing systems.

Research areas: computer architecture; computer systems; near-data processing; formal methods; sustainability.

Education ____

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D in Computer Science

Advisor: Nathan Beckmann

June 2023 - Present

University of Portland

Portland, OR

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, Cum Laude
MINOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING.

Aug. 2019 - May 2023

Publications

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

IEEE CAL 2023

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

WDDSA @ MICRO 2022

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Honors & Awards ___

2023 **NSF Graduate Research Fellowship**, National Science Foundation

2023 Cum Laude, University of Portland

2023 **Outstanding Student Award**, Computer Science Department, University of Portland

2020 **Tau Beta Pi Induction**, Oregon Gamma, University of Portland

All terms Dean's List, University of Portland

2019-2023 **President's Scholarship**, University of Portland

2019-2023 FIRST Robotics Scholarship, University of Portland

Professional Experience _____

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

June 2023 - Present

June 2024 - August 2024

Researching in computer architecture and computer systems.

San Jose, CA

· Researching near-cache computing systems.

• Mentor: Alireza Kaviani

RESEARCH INTERN

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2022 - May 2023

- Researched design methodologies for novel cache coherence protocols and designed protocols for cache-attached accelerators.
- Worked with Prof. Nathan Beckmann as part of the REU in Software Engineering.

Team Lift

Portland, OR; Karonga, Malawi

SENIOR CAPSTONE

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

1

• Designed a connected network of sensors and computation nodes for an infrastructure-limited environment in Malawi, Africa.

University of Portland Portland, OR

Undergraduate Researcher Jan. 2022 - May 2022

• Investigated CPU specialization methods to increase the performance and efficiency of Viterbi Decoding.

Intelligent, Complex, Adaptive, and Networks Lab

University of Portland

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2021 - August 2021

· Researched EEG-based view of comprehension of truth statements to understand how humans process undefined statements.

Talks and Presentations

Kobold: Coherence for Near-Cache Accelerators

CMU Parallel Data Lab Workshop, 7

Nov. 2023

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

WDDSA @ MICRO, 2 Oct. 2022

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

SRC @ MICRO, 3 Oct. 2022

Comparison of Computer Architecture Specialization Methods for Performance and

University of Portland Founders' Day, 12 April 2022

Power Efficiency

Service & Leadership _____

Graduate Student Assembly

Carnegie Mellon University

COMPUTER SCIENCE DEPARTMENT REPRESENTATIVE

Fall 2023 - Present

• PhD student representing the Computer Science Department in the CMU Graduate Student Assembly.

PhD Open House Committee

Carnegie Mellon University

Spring 2024

• Organized Open House for prospective PhD students.

Tau Beta Pi University of Portland

OREGON GAMMA CHAPTER PRESIDENT

2021 - 2022

2020 - 2023

• Planned meetings and activities to engage club members ranging from career development to design competitions.

Society of Women Engineers

University of Portland

• Mentored freshman girls in the engineering program.

Teaching _____

University of Portland

Theory of Computation (CS 357) Grader, Fall 2022 Digital Systems Design (EE 332) Tutor, Spring 2022 Signals & Systems (EE 262) Tutor, Spring 2022 Logic Design (EE 231) Grader and Tutor, Fall 2021 Electrical Circuits (EE 261) Tutor, Fall 2021-Spring 2022 Electrical Circuits Lab (EE 271) Lab Assistant, Spring 2021

Mentoring

Research Advising

Bas Yoovidhya (CMU CS masters student)

Fall 2023 - Present

Mayne Mei (University of Michigan CS undergraduate, advised with Prof. Yatin Manerkar)

Fall 2023

Skills_____

Computer Architecture Tools

Programming Languages C, C++, Python, Java, Assembly (including RISC-V), MATLAB, Haskell, Verilog HDL, LaTeX Parallel Computing Experience in parallel algorithm design and programming using CUDA, OneTBB, and pthreads Experience using gem5, SLICC, McPat, Murphi Model Checker, CACTI, ProtoGen/HieraGen, Pin tools **Other** Proficiency with Unix, SSH, Git/Github, Xcode, VSCode. Experience with LLVM